Soumyadeep Chatterjee

CONTACT 609 Grand Fir Ave, Apt. 7 INFORMATION Sunnyvale, CA 94086 soumyachat@gmail.com Phone: 612-321-1212

Summary

I have more than 5 years of experience in designing and implementing machine learning and data mining models and algorithms for predictive modeling. My work has focused on high-dimensional models for learning interactions and statistical relationships between large number of entities from limited training data.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Ph.D., Computer Science & Engg., 2009 – 2015

• Thesis: High Dimensional Statistical Models: Applications to Climate

• Advisor: Arindam Banerjee, Ph.D

• GPA: 3.88/4.0

Jadavpur University, Kolkata, India

B.E., Dept. of Electronics & Telecomm. Engg., 2005 – 2009

• GPA: 9.35/10.0

EMPLOYMENT

Research Scientist

October 2015 – present

Personalization Science

Yahoo! Labs

Research Intern June 2014 – August 2014

Personalization Sciences,

Yahoo! Labs

Research Assistant May 2010 – August 2015

Dept. of Computer Science & Engg., University of Minnesota, Twin Cities Advisor: Arindam Banerjee, Ph.D.

Graduate School Fellow

September 2009 – May 2012

Dept. of Computer Science & Engg., University of Minnesota, Twin Cities

SKILLS

- **Programming Languages:** Python, MATLAB, R, C++, Hadoop (basic), Java (basic)
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Mac OS X
- Coursework: Machine Learning; Artificial Intelligence; Sparse Matrix Computations; Probability and Stochastic Processes; Graph Theory; Real Analysis; Information Theory and Coding; Software Engineering.

Publications

A. Asiaee Taheri, S. Chatterjee and A. Banerjee, "Regularized Structured Estimation in High-Dimensions with Noisy Designs", SIAM Intl. Conference on Data Mining 2016.

- 2. **S.** Chatterjee, S. Chen and A. Banerjee, "Generalized Dantzig Selector: Application to the *k*-support norm", Advances in Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS), 2014.
- 3. A.Goncalves, P. Das, S. Chatterjee, V. Sivakumar, F. J. Von Zuben and A. Banerjee, "Multi-task Sparse Structure Learning", International Conference on Information and Knowledge Management (CIKM), 2014.
- 4. A. R. Ganguly, E. A. Kodra, A. Banerjee, S. Boriah, S. Chatterjee, S. Chatterjee, A. Choudhary, D. Das, J. Faghmous, P. Ganguli, S. Ghosh, K. Hayhoe, C. Hays, W. Hendrix, Q. Fu, J. Kawale, D. Kumar, V. Kumar, S. Liess, R. Mawalagedara, V. Mithal, R. Oglesby, K. Salvi, P. K. Snyder, K. Steinhaeuser, D. Wang and D. Wuebbles, "Toward enhanced understanding and prediction of climate extremes using physics-guided data mining techniques". Nonlinear Processes in Geophysics, 2014.
- 5. H. Wang, F. Fazayeli, **S. Chatterjee** and A. Banerjee, "Gaussian Copula Precision Estimation with Missing Values", International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2014.
- 6. S. Chatterjee, A. Banerjee, S. Chatterjee and A. Ganguly, "Mixture of Regression Models for Precipitation Prediction", The Second International Workshop on Climate Informatics (CI), 2012.
- S. Chatterjee, K. Steinhaeuser, A. Banerjee, S. Chatterjee and A. Ganguly, "Sparse Group Lasso: Consistency and Climate Applications", SIAM Intl. Conference on Data Mining 2012 (Best Student Paper Award).
- 8. **S. Chatterjee**, K. Bhattacharjee and A. Konar, "A Simple and Robust Algorithm for Microarray Data Clustering Based on Gene Population-Variance Ratio Metric", Biotechnology Journal, Vol. 4, Issue 9, 2009.
- 9. K. Bhattacharjee, **S. Chatterjee** and A. Konar, "A Novel Clustering Method for Gene Microarray Data Using Intra-Cluster Distance and Variance", IEEE Intl. Advanced Computing Conference, 2009 (IACC-09).
- 10. S. Chatterjee, K. Bhattacharjee, A. Konar and A. Nagar, "A Robust Clustering Method for Gene Microarray Data Using Genetic Algorithm", European Modeling Symposium, 2008 (EMS-08), September 2008.

AWARDS & SCHOLARSHIPS

- Best Student Paper Award at the SIAM International Conference on Data Mining (SDM), 2012.
- Travel Fellowship for poster presented at The Second International Workshop on Climate Informatics 2012.
- Travel Award for paper presented at SDM 2012.
- 3 year Graduate School Fellowship (2009-2012) from Univ. of Minnesota Twin Cities.
- 4-year J. C. Bose National Science Talent Search (JBNSTS) Senior Scholarship, 2005–2009.